In the last video, we talked
在上一讲中，我们讨论了(字幕翻译：中国海洋大学 刘竞)
about the process of evaluating
评估一个
an anomaly detection algorithm and
异常检测算法的过程
there we started to use some
当时我们使用了一些带有标签的数据,
labelled data, with examples
对于使用的例子，我们知道
that we knew were either anomalous
它们要么是正常的
or not anomalous, with y equals 1 or y equals 0.
要么是异常的，y要么等于1，要么等于0.
So the question then arises, if
所以问题就出来了，
we have this labeled data,
假如我们有这些带有标签的数据，
we have some examples that are
我们有一些例子，我们知道
known to be anomalies and some
它们是异常，还有一些例子
that are known not to be not
我们知道它们是正常的，
anomalies, why don't we
那么为什么我们不用
just use a supervised learning algorithm,
一个监督学习算法，
so why don't we just use
那么为什么我们不用一个
logistic regression or a neural
逻辑回归或者一个神经
network to try to
网络算法去试图
learn directly from our labeled
从我们的带标签的数据中直接学习,
data, to predict whether y equals one or y equals zero.
并去预测是否y等于1或者y等于0呢？
In this video, I'll try to
在这个视频中，我将尝试去
share with you some of
和大学一起分享
the thinking and some guidelines for
一些思想以及指导方针，这将用于
when you should probably use an
当你可能会使用一个
anomaly detection algorithm and when
异常检测算法的情况，但是当你
it might be more fruitful to consider
使用一个监督学习算法时
using a supervised learning algorithm.
将会更加有效的情况。
This slide shows, what are
从这个幻灯片可以看到，
the settings under which you should
什么情况下你
maybe use anomaly detection versus
很可能使用异常检测算法，
when supervised learning might be more fruitful.
以及什么情况下使用监督学习算法更有效。
If you have a problem with a
如果你有一个问题，问题中有
very small number of positive
很少数量的正例，
examples, and remember examples of
记住，当这些例子
y equals one are the
的y的取值等于1时，
anomalous examples, then
它们是异常的例子，
you might consider using an anomaly detection algorithm inset.
那么你可以考虑使用一个嵌入的异常检测算法。
So having 0 to 20,
所以如果有0到20个
maybe up to 50 positive examples,
可能最多到50个正例，
might be pretty typical, and usually,
这可能是很典型的，并且通常情况下，
we have such a small set
我们有很少数量的
of positive examples,
正例，
we are going to save the positive
我们会把这些正例保留下来，
examples just for the cross
仅是把它们作为交叉
validation sets and test sets.
验证集和测试集。
In contrast, in a typical
与些相反，在一个典型的
normal anomaly detection setting,
正规的异常检测下，
we will often have a relatively
我们通常将会有一个相对更大
large number of negative examples,
数量的反例，
of these normal examples of
比如说这些正常的
normal aircraft engines.
航空发动机。
And we can then use this very
我们可以用这些更大
large number of negative examples,
数量的反例，
with which to fit the model
去拟合
p of x.  And so, there is
关于x的模型p. 因此，
this idea in many anomaly detection
在许多异常检测
applications, you have
应用中有这样一个思想，
very few positive examples, and
你有很少的正例，
lots of negative examples, and when
很多的反例，
we are doing the process of
当我们在估计关于x的模型p的过程中，
estimating p of x, of fitting all those Gaussian parameters,
当我们拟合这些高斯参数时，
we need only negative examples to do that.
我们只需要反例就够了。
So if you have a lot of negative data,
所以，如果你有大量的反例数据，
we can still fit to p of x pretty well.
你仍然可以很好的拟合关于x的模型p.
In contrast, for supervised learning,
与此相反，对于监督学习而言，
more typically we would have
更为典型情况是我们需要
a reasonably large number of
有一个合理的数量比较大的
both positive and negative examples.
正例和反例。
And so this is one
所以，这是一个
way to look at your problem
观察你的问题的方式
and decide if you should use
以决定你是应该使用
an anomaly detection algorithm or a supervised learning algorithm.
一个异常检测算法还是一个监督学习算法。
Here is another way people often think about anomaly detection algorithms.
这有另外一个人们经常思考异常检测算法的方式。
So, for anomaly detection applications
确实如此，对于许多异常检测的应用，
often there are many
经常有许多
different types of anomalies.
不同类型的异常。
So think about aircraft engines.
比如航空发动机。
You know there are so many different ways for aircraft engines to go wrong.
你们知道当发动机异常时，有许多不同的异常形式。
Right? There are so many things that could go wrong that could break an aircraft engine.
对吧？有许多方面可以出现故障，打断航空发动机的正常工作。
And so, if that's the
因此，如果情况就是这样，
case and you have a pretty small
你有很少数量的
set of positive examples, then
正例，那么
it can be difficult for
这将很困难，
an algorithm to learn from your small
如果使用一个算法从你的
set of positive examples what the anomalies look like.
这么少数量的正例中去学习异常是什么。
And in particular,
尤其是
you know, future anomalies may look
你也知道，未来可能出现的异常
nothing like the ones you've seen so far.
可能与你至今见过的异常完全不同。
So maybe in your set
可能在你的
of positive examples, maybe you
正例中，有5个或者10个，或者20个
had seen 5 or 10, or 20
你已经见过的
different ways that an aircraft engine could go wrong.
航空发动机发生故障的不同情况。
But maybe tomorrow, you
但是，可能到了明天，你
need to detect a totally
就需要去检测一个全新
new set, a totally new
的集合，一个全新
type of anomaly, a totally
异常类型， 一个全
new way for an aircraft
新的航空
engine to be broken that
发动机故障的方式，
you have just never seen before,
而且这个你之前从来就没有见过，
and if that is the case,
并且，假如情况就是这样，
then it might be more
那么它将更
promising to just model
有希望，如果去为反例建立
the negative examples, with a
一个模型，
sort of a Gaussian model
模型是一个种关于x的高斯
P of X. Rather than try
模型P。而不是很费劲地
too hard to model the positive
去建立模型去拟合
examples, because, you know,
正例，因为，你也知道
tomorrow's anomaly may be
明天的异常可能
nothing like the ones you've seen so far.
与你至今见过的这些完全不同。
In contrast, in some other
与此相反，在一些其它的
problems you have enough
问题中，你有足够的
positive examples for an algorithm
正例使得一个算法
to get a sense of what the positive examples are like.
能够学习到正例是什么样子的。
And in particular, if you
并且尤其是，假如你
think that future positive examples
认为未来的正例
are likely to be similar
很可能与你当前
to ones in the training set,
训练集中的正例很相似。
then in that setting it might
那么，在这种情况下，
be more reasonable to have a supervised learning algorithm,
使用一个监督学习算法将会更合理，
that looks at a lot of
算法通过察看
the positive examples, looks at a
正例，察看很多的
lot of the negative examples, and
反例，通过观察到的这些知识，
uses that to try to distinguish between positives and negatives.
去尝试区分正例和反例。
So hopefully this gives you
希望这些可以让你
a sense of if you have
明白，当你有一个
a specific problem you should think
特定的问题，你能知道
about using the anomaly
你应该使用异常检测算法
detection algorithm or a supervised learning algorithm.
还是监督学习算法。
And the key difference really is,
最关键的不同之处在于
that in anomaly detection, after
在异常检测中，
we have such a small
我们只有很少数量的
number of positive examples that there
正例，以致于对于一个
is not possible, for a learning
学习算法而言，它是不可能
algorithm to learn that much from the positive examples.
从正例中学习到足够的知识。
And so what we do instead,
所以，我们应该做的是
is take a large set of
采用大量的
negative examples, and have it just
反例， 并且让它学习
learned a lot, learned p
很多，学习到
of x from just the negative
关于反例的，关于x的模型p,
examples of the normal aircraft engines, say.
例如这些反例就是正常的航空发动机。
And we reserve the small
我们保留小数量的
number of positive examples for evaluating our algorithm
正例去评估我们的算法，
to use in either the cross validation sets or the test sets.
这一少部分的正例要么用于交叉验证集要么用于测试集。
And just as a side comment about
仅仅是对这
these many different types of
许多不同类型的异常
anomalies, you know, in
的一个方面的说明，你知道的，
some earlier videos we talked
在前几讲的视频中，我们讨论的
about the email SPAM examples.
垃圾邮件的例子。
In those examples, there are
在这些例子中，实际有
actually many different types of SPAM email.
有许多不同类型的垃圾邮件。
The SPAM email is trying to
有种垃圾邮件企图向你
sell you things spam email, trying to steal your passwords,
兜售物品，企图偷取你的密码，
this is called fishing emails, and many different types of SPAM emails.
这种叫做钓鱼邮件，而且有许多种其它类型的垃圾邮件。
But for the SPAM problem, we usually
但是对于垃圾邮件问题，我们通常
have enough examples of spam
有足够的垃圾
email to see, you know,
邮件例子去观察，你也知道，
most of these different types of
对于这许多不同类型的垃圾邮件，
SPAM email, because we have a
因为我们有大量的
large set of examples of
的例子，
SPAM, and that's why we
这就是为什么我们
usually think of SPAM as
通常把垃圾邮件问题看成是
a supervised learning setting, even
一个监督学习问题，
though, you know, there may be
即使我们都知道，有许多
many different types of SPAM.
不同各类的垃圾邮件。
And so, if we look at
因此， 假如我们
some applications of anomaly detection
通过于监督学习相对比，
versus supervised learning, we'll find
观察一些使用异常监测的应用，我们会
that, in fraud detection, if
发现，在欺骗检测中，
you have many different types
如果你有许多不同的方式
of ways for people to
使人们可以
try to commit fraud, and a
尝试欺骗，并且有相对
relevantly small training set, a
较少的训练集，
small number of fraudulent users
以及网站上只有很小一部分的欺骗性
on your website, then I would use an anomaly detection algorithm.
用户，那么我将使用一个异常检测算法。
I should say, if you
我应该说，假如你有，
have, if you are very a
假如你是一个
major online retailer, and
大的在线零售商，
if you actually have had a
如果实际上
lot of people try to commit
在你的网站上有很多人
fraud on your website, so if
尝试欺骗，那么
you actually have a lot of
你实际上有许多例子，
examples where y equals 1, then
这些例子的y等于1，那么，
you know, sometimes fraud detection
你也知道，有时欺骗检测
could actually shift over to the supervised learning column.
实际上可以转换成监督学习问题。
But, if you
但是，如果你
haven't seen that many
还没有见过许多例子，
examples of users doing
在这些例子中，用户
strange things on your website
在你的网站上做奇怪的事情，
then, more frequently, fraud detection
那么，更常见的是，欺骗检测
is actually treated as an
实际是被异常检测算法来处理了，
anomaly detection algorithm, rather than one of the supervised learning algorithm.
而不是被监督学习算法处理。
Other examples, we talked about
其它的例子，我们讨论过的
manufacturing already, hopefully you'll
生产问题，希望你可以
see more normal examples,
看到更多正常的例子，
not that many anomalies.
而不是那么多异常例子。
But then again, for some manufacturing
但是，话又说回来，对于一些生产
processes, if you're
过程，如果你在
manufacturing very large volumes
进行大量生产，
and you've seen a lot
并且你已经见到了许多
of bad examples, maybe manufacturing
坏的例子，可能生产问题
could shift to the supervised learning column as well.
也转换到了监督学习问题。
But, if you haven't seen that
但是，假如你在过去的产品中
many bad examples of
还没有见过许多坏的例子，
the old products, then I'll do this anomaly detection.
那么，我将做异常检测。
Monitoring machines in the
在数据中心
data center, again similar
的监视机上，
sorts of arguments apply.
也是相似的情况。
Whereas, email SPAM
然而，对于
classification, weather prediction, and classifying
垃圾邮件的分类，天气预报，
cancers, if you have
关于癌症的分类这类问题，如果
equal numbers of positive and
你有相同数量的正例
negative examples, a lot of you
和反例，你们有许多，
have many examples of your
这样的例子，在这些例子中，
positive and your negative
你有许多正例和反例，
examples, then, we would tend to
那么，我们会把这些情况
treat all of these as supervised learning problems.
都采用监督学习来处理。
So, hopefully, that gives you
所以，我希望，这些可以
a sense of what are the
让你们明白什么样的
properties of a learning
学习方法的特征
problem that would cause you to
让你选择
treat it as an anomaly
采用异常检测算法去处理，
detention problem verses a supervised learning
什么样的特征让你选择采用监督
problem.
学习算法去处理。
And for many of the problems that are
对于各种各样的技术公司
faced by various technology companies
所面临的问题中，
and so on, we actually are
当我们实际
in these settings where we have
处于这样的情况下，当我们
very few or sometimes zero
有很少甚至是没有
positive training examples,
正训练例子时，
maybe there are so many
可能会大量的
different types of anomalies that we've never
不同类型的我们从
seen them before, and for those
没有见过的异常，对于这样的
sorts of problems, very often,
问题，通常情况下
the algorithm that is used
使用的算法是
is an anomaly detection algorithm.
一个异常检测算法。